<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evergreen</title>
    <description>Never stop growing.
</description>
    <link>https://ianrahman.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ianrahman.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:20:54 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:20:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:15:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/jekyll/update/2016/02/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/jekyll/update/2016/02/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Commit</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;The beginning is the most important part of the work.&quot;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Plato&quot;&gt;Plato&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been away from the blogging scene for quite a while now, suddenly today it dawned upon me that I need to start writing/posting again. My writing is a little bit rusty now, and I need to brush on that. Anyways, the moment I thought about blogging, Wordpress flashed in my mind. Well, I used Wordpress &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in the past and it worked well for a while, then I had to face issues like high-traffic and high CPU load and unexpected spikes in my server. Well, those weren’t too much trouble, I would avoid fixing those bugs if I was busy, and sometimes I would leave the system untouched for 2 days straight and let the server admins frown and try to mitigate the outage (I had a pretty straight forward deal with my hosting provider, that no matter what, they can’t shut down my website). The PHP runtime errors weren’t a big deal, the hundreds of thousands of SQL database queries weren’t a trouble, sometimes the site would run a tad bit slower than average, but it was OK overall for me. A sample of the emails I would receive from my hosting provider is given below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tickets@hostgator.com
10/11/10

to hmfaysal 
Hello, 


I apologize, but I was forced to suspend the script &quot;/home/hmfaysal/public_html/hmfaysal.com/index.php&quot; as it was causing a high load on the server, and due to it affecting all of the other accounts on the system, I was forced to take immediate action for the health of the server.g 

I did notice that this was a Wordpress installation, and would recommend that you enable caching for it.

Please note that if you already have caching enabled, you will need to take more action such as looking into any high use modules or plugins, and seeing if there are any updates, or possibly any that you can disable to reduce the load that your site causes. 

If you reply back to this with your IP address (http://www.hostgator.com/ip.shtml) we will be more than happy to go ahead enable HTTP access for you, so that you can safely work on the script without it causing further issues. Please let me know how you would like to proceed.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the game was changed when my site got hacked. Wordpress is notorious in getting hacked. The PHP code libraries are huge, and while Automattic tries to keep it relatively clean and bug free, bugs do persist among the thousands of lines of codes and every once in a while a bug gets discovered by the code breakers. If the bug can be exploited in some way to gain access of the site, the code breakers tend to do some serious damage. While I wasn’t been exclusively targeted by such individuals, I was part of a victimized group who used the same version of Wordpress, and all of our sites got defaced by some mass defacing software. Although it didn’t do serious damage, as I have daily off-site backup, I became dubious about the Wordpress platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this time around, while I was still brainstorming for ideas and theme designs and what not, I decided to go back to Jekyll, or you may say, rather old school. Why not use plain static HTML files with some CSS styling and JS animations? Static sites are impossible to hack, as there are no codes needed to be run on the server. The only way a static site can be compromised if the code breakers have access to your FTP account. I have used Jekyll in the past during my college years. I was working as a Teaching Assistant in the Mathematics Dept, and I was supposed to post weekly course materials on the course website. The trouble was my Alma maters IT dept didn’t allow dynamic sites to run on the nodes, and I wasn’t going download the HTML files, edit them with Sublime text, and push them back onto the server every week. So I used Jekyll and GIT Version Control to do that for me. And it was so efficient that I would post materials daily instead of weekly. It was like love on first use. But Wordpress had lots of theme choices and for my personal site I decided to use Wordpress anyways disregarding the simpleness and speed static sites provided. After the takeover of my Wordpress powered blog happened, I turned to self written PHP sites and static sites completely. I have built a social network based on PHP for my peer group which is highly secure but when it comes down to speed it lags behind. So I built this site using Jekyll, a blog aware static site generator. I hope this site will perform as envisioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This domain previously hosted a Wordpress blog. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/personal/2014/05/15/first-commit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/personal/2014/05/15/first-commit.html</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABOUT HMFAYSAL OMEGA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA is a minimalist, beautiful, responsive theme for Jekyll designed for engineers as well as writers who want their content to take front and center. This theme elegantly wraps each page and post with featured images complementing the content. HMFAYSAL OMEGA (named after the Greek Alphabet) complements Jekyll’s minimalist, content-first approach with gorgeous typography and subtle design elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write well, write beautifully, write responsively!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#twitter-bootstrap-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-twitter-bootstrap-3&quot;&gt;Twitter Bootstrap 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#option-to-set-parallax-featured-image-that-wraps-your-post-in-header-and-footer&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-option-to-set-parallax-featured-image-that-wraps-your-post-in-header-and-footer&quot;&gt;Option to set Parallax featured image that wraps your post in header and footer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#variable-templates-for-articles-link-quotation-and-status-updates&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-variable-templates-for-articles-link-quotation-and-status-updates&quot;&gt;Variable templates for articles, link, quotation and status updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#responsive-images-and-magnific-popup-lightbox&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-responsive-images-and-magnific-popup-lightbox&quot;&gt;Responsive images and Magnific Popup Lightbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#plugin-freegithub-pages-deployment-ready&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-plugin-freegithub-pages-deployment-ready&quot;&gt;Plugin-free/Github Pages Deployment Ready&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#read-time-calculator-calculation-of-post-read-time-based-on-word-count&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-read-time-calculator-calculation-of-post-read-time-based-on-word-count&quot;&gt;Read time Calculator: Calculation of post read-time based on word count&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#simple-search-that-overlays-results-based-on-post-title&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-simple-search-that-overlays-results-based-on-post-title&quot;&gt;Simple search that overlays results based on post title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#display-mathematical-equations-beautifully-via-mathjax&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-display-mathematical-equations-beautifully-via-mathjax&quot;&gt;Display mathematical equations beautifully via MathJax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#css3-transitions-and-svg-graphics-for-better-performance&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-css3-transitions-and-svg-graphics-for-better-performance&quot;&gt;CSS3 transitions and SVG graphics for better performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ability-to-turn-of-animations-in-configyml&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ability-to-turn-of-animations-in-configyml&quot;&gt;Ability to turn of animations in _config.yml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#readable-typography-to-make-your-words-shine&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-readable-typography-to-make-your-words-shine&quot;&gt;Readable typography to make your words shine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#google-fonts&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-google-fonts&quot;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#other-features&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-other-features&quot;&gt;Other features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#designed-by-an-electrical-engineer&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-designed-by-an-electrical-engineer&quot;&gt;Designed by an Electrical Engineer&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#questions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-questions&quot;&gt;Questions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#requests&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-requests&quot;&gt;Requests?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#license&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter-bootstrap-3&quot;&gt;Twitter Bootstrap 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the latest Bootstrap its easy to update and customize to your own needs. Plus the power of the mobile first front-end framework adds to faster and easier web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the list of theme elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;option-to-set-parallax-featured-image-that-wraps-your-post-in-header-and-footer&quot;&gt;Option to set Parallax featured image that wraps your post in header and footer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought an article should wrap up in the end. What better way to do it other than wrapping it around with pictures? As we all know, a picture is worth a thousand words. Why not put 500 of those in the header and the rest in the footer to help writers tell their story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;variable-templates-for-articles-link-quotation-and-status-updates&quot;&gt;Variable templates for articles, link, quotation and status updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme employs &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;post.type&quot;&lt;/code&gt; to assign variable templates article entries, link posts, quotation and status updates. No other Jekyll theme offers this functionality. In the future, more &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;post.types&quot;&lt;/code&gt; will be included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsive-images-and-magnific-popup-lightbox&quot;&gt;Responsive images and Magnific Popup Lightbox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme supports responsive images and uses a responsive lightbox to showcase larger images. Images also use CSS3 transitions to turn to B&amp;amp;W when not hovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plugin-freegithub-pages-deployment-ready&quot;&gt;Plugin-free/Github Pages Deployment Ready&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although featuring a mind-boggling number of features, this theme has been coded in such a way that it can be compiled without the usage of any plugins whatsoever. You do not have to worry about compatibility. Its ready for deployment on the Github Pages immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;read-time-calculator-calculation-of-post-read-time-based-on-word-count&quot;&gt;Read time Calculator: Calculation of post read-time based on word count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been enjoying Medium.com as of lately and I simply love their Estimated Reading Time (ERT) of an article feature. What it does, it takes the word count of an article and calculates the ERT based on the average reading speed (ARS). While ARS is simply an estimation and it differs from person-to-person, Medium uses 180 Words-Per-Minute (WPM) as their ARS. I figured out that ARS in general is around 200 WPM. You can turn on or off this feature in the _config.yml file. Very recommended to use this feature as it increases user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simple-search-that-overlays-results-based-on-post-title&quot;&gt;Simple search that overlays results based on post title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme provides search using Christian Fei’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/christian-fei/Simple-Jekyll-Search&quot;&gt;Simple Jekyll jQuery plugin&lt;/a&gt; if you choose to enable search functionality in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. Clicking search will trigger a fullscreen overlay that searches post titles’ using an autogenerated JSON file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;display-mathematical-equations-beautifully-via-mathjax&quot;&gt;Display mathematical equations beautifully via MathJax&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both inline and displayed equations can be rendered via MathJax. HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme supports MathJax natively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css3-transitions-and-svg-graphics-for-better-performance&quot;&gt;CSS3 transitions and SVG graphics for better performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme uses subtle CSS3 transitions and SVG to showcase subtle animations for viewer pleasure. This ensures that optimal performance is guaranteed during page viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-turn-of-animations-in-configyml&quot;&gt;Ability to turn of animations in _config.yml&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme avoids Javascript animations to increase website performance. But if you are still facing some lag in your test device, you can turn off the animations in the _config.yml file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;readable-typography-to-make-your-words-shine&quot;&gt;Readable typography to make your words shine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme is a minimal, simple and responsive Jekyll theme built for maximum readability. The main design focus of HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme is the typography and the clean design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-fonts&quot;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme uses Google Webfonts instead of Adobe Edgefonts for performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-features&quot;&gt;Other features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disqus comments if you choose to enable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple and clear permalink structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Footer Menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;361 Fontawesome icons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tags for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/opengraph/&quot;&gt;Open Graph&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/docs/cards&quot;&gt;Twitter Cards&lt;/a&gt; for a better social sharing experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beautifully crafted &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/404.html&quot;&gt;404 page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/categories/&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/tags/&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/a&gt; pages for viewers pleasure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stylesheets for Pygments and Coderay to make your code examples look snazzy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sitemap for search engines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designed-by-an-electrical-engineer&quot;&gt;Designed by an Electrical Engineer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA Theme was designed by Hossain Mohd Faysal – an Electrical Engineer. I have to confess I am not a designer. So when you download this theme, you have to know you are not getting the best designed elements out there, but instead what you are getting is extremely clean code even though the site uses some highly complex liquid logic expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a problem getting something to work or want to know why I setup something in a certain way? Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/documentation/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt; or ping me on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hmfaysal&quot;&gt;@hmfaysal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hmfaysal/hmfaysal-omega-theme/issues/new&quot;&gt;file a GitHub Issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requests&quot;&gt;Requests?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have some specific requests for this theme, or if you need help custom coding some elements, message me on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hmfaysal&quot;&gt;@hmfaysal&lt;/a&gt; or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#109;&amp;#102;&amp;#097;&amp;#121;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#104;&amp;#109;&amp;#102;&amp;#097;&amp;#121;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme is free and open source software, distributed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/license/&quot;&gt;The MIT License&lt;/a&gt;. So feel free to use this Jekyll theme on your site without linking back to me or using a disclaimer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to give me credit somewhere on your blog or tweet a shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hmfaysal&quot;&gt;@hmfaysal&lt;/a&gt;, that would be pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/theme-setup/2014/01/12/about-hmfaysal-omega.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/theme-setup/2014/01/12/about-hmfaysal-omega.html</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>HMFAYSAL OMEGA</category>
        
        <category>Features</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Theme-Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Status Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Hello. This is a status post. Click here to learn about it more :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, you can enter additional details about your status update. Only the first paragraph &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[p:first-child]&lt;/code&gt; will be shown in the home page :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start a status post, simply run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rake newstatus[&#39;Some Status Title&#39;]&lt;/code&gt; in the command line. Or if you want to create the post by yourself, make sure your post contains the following contents in your post’s Front Matter YAML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
type: status
title: &quot;Sample Status Title&quot;
description: 
headline: 
modified: YYYY-MM-DD
category: status
image: 
  feature: 
comments: true
mathjax: 
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/11/a-status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/11/a-status.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>status</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Sample-Posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Theme Elements</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve put together a little post to introduce you to the HMFAYSAL OMEGA theme and get you started with Markdown. Go ahead and edit this post to get going and learn how it all works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Elements&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#elements&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-elements&quot;&gt;ELEMENTS&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lists&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lists&quot;&gt;LISTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#links&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-links&quot;&gt;LINKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-about-images&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-about-images&quot;&gt;WHAT ABOUT IMAGES?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#and-videos&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-and-videos&quot;&gt;AND VIDEOS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#equations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-equations&quot;&gt;EQUATIONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-logo&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-logo&quot;&gt;THE LOGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#icons&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-icons&quot;&gt;ICONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#quoting&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-quoting&quot;&gt;QUOTING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#working-with-code&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-working-with-code&quot;&gt;WORKING WITH CODE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ready-for-a-break&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ready-for-a-break&quot;&gt;READY FOR A BREAK?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fancy-some-columns&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-fancy-some-columns&quot;&gt;FANCY SOME COLUMNS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#buttons&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-buttons&quot;&gt;BUTTONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#advanced-usage&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-advanced-usage&quot;&gt;ADVANCED USAGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;elements&quot;&gt;ELEMENTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in markdown is really easy. In any editor like notepad, you simply write as you normally would. Where appropriate, you can use formatting shortcuts to style your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lists&quot;&gt;LISTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item number one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item number two
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A nested item&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A final item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or with numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to buy some milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink the milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tweet that I remembered to buy the milk, and drank it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;LINKS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to link to a source? No problem. If you put the url in this format, like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[http://alum.mit.edu/www/hmfaysal](http://alum.mit.edu/www/hmfaysal)&lt;/code&gt; - it’ll automatically be linked up like &lt;a href=&quot;http://alum.mit.edu/www/hmfaysal&quot;&gt;http://alum.mit.edu/www/hmfaysal&lt;/a&gt;. But if you want to customize your anchor text, you can do that too! Here’s a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://alum.mit.edu/www/hmfaysal&quot; title=&quot;HMFAYSAL&#39;s Blog&quot;&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt;. Neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-images&quot;&gt;WHAT ABOUT IMAGES?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images work too! And they are responsive! Already know the URL of the image you want to include in your article? Images are responsive and uses lightbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (16).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (16).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (14).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (13).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (20).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (19).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/articles/sample-post-images/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; to learn about including images in your post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-videos&quot;&gt;AND VIDEOS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video embeds are responsive and scale with the width of the main content block with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fitvidsjs.com/&quot;&gt;FitVids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equations&quot;&gt;EQUATIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you an engineer? Or a mathematician? Want to post some equations in your Jekyll blog for the world to see? No problem. HMFAYSAL OMEGA has MathJax built in to beautifully render your equations in the browser. To use MathJax simply turn on the MathJax feature by declaring in the Front YAML Matter like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mathjax: true&lt;/code&gt;, then wrapping your equation between &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$...$$&lt;/code&gt; will produce something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;math display=&quot;block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;mstyle&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
 &lt;mfrac&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
        &lt;mrow&gt;
          &lt;mn&gt;2&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;mi&gt;π&lt;!-- π --&gt;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;∮&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;γ&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;z&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;z&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;−&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;z&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/mstyle&gt;
&lt;/math&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-logo&quot;&gt;THE LOGO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which image you want to use yet? That’s ok too. Leave yourself a descriptive placeholder and keep writing. Come back later and change the image in the _config.yml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;icons&quot;&gt;ICONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme includes over 360 fontawesome icons. To use an icon go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fontawesome.io/3.2.1/icons/&quot;&gt;Fontawesome&lt;/a&gt; website and click on the desired icon to find the appropriate tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;icon-cogs&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-youtube-sign&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-coffee&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-cloud-upload&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-camera&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-comments-alt&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-eye-open&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-heart&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-globe&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quoting&quot;&gt;QUOTING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a link isn’t enough, you want to quote someone on what they’ve said. It was probably very wisdomous. Is wisdomous a word? Find out in a future release when I introduce spellcheck! For now - it’s definitely a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wisdomous - it’s definitely a word.
&lt;small&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Hossain Mohd Faysal&quot;&gt;Hossain Mohd Faysal&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-code&quot;&gt;WORKING WITH CODE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a streak of geek? We’ve got you covered there, too. You can write inline &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; blocks really easily with back ticks. Want to show off something more comprehensive? 4 spaces of indentation gets you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.awesome-thing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;block&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about syntax highlighting &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/articles/code-highlighting-post/&quot;&gt;in this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-for-a-break&quot;&gt;READY FOR A BREAK?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw 4 or more dashes down on any new line and you’ve got yourself a fancy new divider. Aw yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fancy-some-columns&quot;&gt;FANCY SOME COLUMNS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;  
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more column combinations, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/personal/fancy-columns/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buttons&quot;&gt;BUTTONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-danger btn-large&quot;&gt;Some danger button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-info btn-large&quot;&gt;Some info button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-warning btn-large&quot;&gt;Some warning button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-success btn-large&quot;&gt;Some success button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary btn-large&quot;&gt;Some primary button&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advanced-usage&quot;&gt;ADVANCED USAGE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one fantastic secret about Markdown. If you want, you can write plain old HTML and it’ll still work! Very flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; placeholder=&quot;I&#39;m an input field!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be enough to get you started. Have fun - and let me know what you think &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hmfaysal&quot;&gt;@hmfaysal&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#109;&amp;#102;&amp;#097;&amp;#121;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#104;&amp;#109;&amp;#102;&amp;#097;&amp;#121;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/theme-setup/2014/01/10/theme-elements.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/theme-setup/2014/01/10/theme-elements.html</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>HMFAYSAL OMEGA</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Theme-Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Gallery Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of what a post with a gallery might look like. If you want to display two or three images next to each other responsively use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; with the appropriate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;. Each instance of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; is auto-numbered and displayed in the caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (4).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (3).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (18).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (17).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (10).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (9).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (6).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (5).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (12).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (11).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (16).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (16).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (14).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (13).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (20).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (19).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (22).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (21).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (24).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (23).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (74).jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ianrahman.com/images/gallery1/photo (73).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photos from my Japan trip.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/photos/2014/01/09/sample-gallery-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/photos/2014/01/09/sample-gallery-post.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>gallery</category>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Quotation Post</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;Any intelligent fool can make things bigger, more complex, and more violent. It takes a touch of genius - and a lot of courage - to move in the opposite direction.&quot;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Albert Einstein&quot;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA theme now supports Quotation posting, made famous by some premium WordPress themes. To make a quotation post, specify the post type as quote in the Front Matter YAML. So the Front Matter YAML should look like something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
type: quote
title: &quot;Sample Quotation Post&quot;
description: 
headline: 
modified: YYYY-MM-DD
category: quote
image: 
  feature: 
comments: true
mathjax: 
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can simply run the rake task command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rake newquote[&quot;Some Quotation Title&quot;]&lt;/code&gt; to generate a skeleton quotation post. Include the intended quotation in Markdown format in your post. A sample quotation in markdown looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; &quot;The Quotation Goes here&quot;
&amp;gt; &amp;lt;small&amp;gt;&amp;lt;cite title=&quot;Name of the Person&quot;&amp;gt;Person&amp;lt;/cite&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add additional details about the quotation in the post. Just make sure the posted quotation goes first in the post, meaning it is the first paragraph of the post. Additional paragraphs can only be seen in the post page. You can also assign a featured image for the post page in the post’s Front Matter YAML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein was born at Ulm, in Württemberg, Germany, on March 14, 1879. Six weeks later the family moved to Munich, where he later on began his schooling at the Luitpold Gymnasium. Later, they moved to Italy and Albert continued his education at Aarau, Switzerland and in 1896 he entered the Swiss Federal Polytechnic School in Zurich to be trained as a teacher in physics and mathematics. In 1901, the year he gained his diploma, he acquired Swiss citizenship and, as he was unable to find a teaching post, he accepted a position as technical assistant in the Swiss Patent Office. In 1905 he obtained his doctor’s degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his stay at the Patent Office, and in his spare time, he produced much of his remarkable work and in 1908 he was appointed Privatdozent in Berne. In 1909 he became Professor Extraordinary at Zurich, in 1911 Professor of Theoretical Physics at Prague, returning to Zurich in the following year to fill a similar post. In 1914 he was appointed Director of the Kaiser Wilhelm Physical Institute and Professor in the University of Berlin. He became a German citizen in 1914 and remained in Berlin until 1933 when he renounced his citizenship for political reasons and emigrated to America to take the position of Professor of Theoretical Physics at Princeton*. He became a United States citizen in 1940 and retired from his post in 1945.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After World War II, Einstein was a leading figure in the World Government Movement, he was offered the Presidency of the State of Israel, which he declined, and he collaborated with Dr. Chaim Weizmann in establishing the Hebrew University of Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein always appeared to have a clear view of the problems of physics and the determination to solve them. He had a strategy of his own and was able to visualize the main stages on the way to his goal. He regarded his major achievements as mere stepping-stones for the next advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of his scientific work, Einstein realized the inadequacies of Newtonian mechanics and his special theory of relativity stemmed from an attempt to reconcile the laws of mechanics with the laws of the electromagnetic field. He dealt with classical problems of statistical mechanics and problems in which they were merged with quantum theory: this led to an explanation of the Brownian movement of molecules. He investigated the thermal properties of light with a low radiation density and his observations laid the foundation of the photon theory of light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his early days in Berlin, Einstein postulated that the correct interpretation of the special theory of relativity must also furnish a theory of gravitation and in 1916 he published his paper on the general theory of relativity. During this time he also contributed to the problems of the theory of radiation and statistical mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1920’s, Einstein embarked on the construction of unified field theories, although he continued to work on the probabilistic interpretation of quantum theory, and he persevered with this work in America. He contributed to statistical mechanics by his development of the quantum theory of a monatomic gas and he has also accomplished valuable work in connection with atomic transition probabilities and relativistic cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After his retirement he continued to work towards the unification of the basic concepts of physics, taking the opposite approach, geometrisation, to the majority of physicists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein’s researches are, of course, well chronicled and his more important works include Special Theory of Relativity (1905), Relativity (English translations, 1920 and 1950), General Theory of Relativity (1916), Investigations on Theory of Brownian Movement (1926), and The Evolution of Physics (1938). Among his non-scientific works, About Zionism (1930), Why War? (1933), My Philosophy (1934), and Out of My Later Years (1950) are perhaps the most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein received honorary doctorate degrees in science, medicine and philosophy from many European and American universities. During the 1920’s he lectured in Europe, America and the Far East, and he was awarded Fellowships or Memberships of all the leading scientific academies throughout the world. He gained numerous awards in recognition of his work, including the Copley Medal of the Royal Society of London in 1925, and the Franklin Medal of the Franklin Institute in 1935.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein’s gifts inevitably resulted in his dwelling much in intellectual solitude and, for relaxation, music played an important part in his life. He married Mileva Maric in 1903 and they had a daughter and two sons; their marriage was dissolved in 1919 and in the same year he married his cousin, Elsa Löwenthal, who died in 1936. He died on April 18, 1955 at Princeton, New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/08/a-quotation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/08/a-quotation.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>quotation</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Sample-Posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Post with a Video</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Video embeds are responsive and scale with the width of the main content block with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fitvidsjs.com/&quot;&gt;FitVids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure if this only effects Kramdown or if it’s an issue with Markdown in general. But adding YouTube video embeds causes errors when building your Jekyll site. To fix add a space between the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags and remove &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;allowfullscreen&lt;/code&gt;. Example below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;width=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;940&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;height=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;529&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/CQJByFp7H38?theme=light&amp;amp;amp;color=white&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;frameborder=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;allowfullscreen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/videos/2014/01/07/video-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/videos/2014/01/07/video-post.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>videos</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fancy Some Columns?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some Premium WordPress themes feature multi-column text entries, which is quite important for academics and engineers like myself for content presentation. HMFAYSAL OMEGA is the first Jekyll Theme to showcase multi-column text entries. HMFAYSAL OMEGA features four types of multi-column configuration, the first being the single column, the others are two, three and four columns. To insert a two-column text entry, simply enter this markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column Two&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which results in two columns with your content and looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For three-column text entry, simply enter this markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column Two&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column Three&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which results in three columns with your content and looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For four-column text entry, simply enter this markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  

&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&amp;gt;Some Content Here for Column One&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which results in four columns with your content and looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also have multiple layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8&quot;&gt;  
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Sed rutrum velit quis magna iaculis lacinia. Aenean sed nisi condimentum, placerat eros sit amet, lacinia purus. Ut sed euismod mauris. Morbi vitae diam quis diam egestas scelerisque a a ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any layout, make sure in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;col-md-#&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;col-md-#&quot;&lt;/code&gt; numbers add up to 12. the You can include any type of elements between the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags, like texts, images, videos etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/07/fancy-columns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/07/fancy-columns.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>columns</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Sample-Posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Mathjax Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;HMFAYSAL OMEGA theme supports both inline and displayed equations via MathJax.  The theme keeps MathJax turned off by default to improve page load speed. MathJax can be turned on from the post’s Front Matter YAML. Simply put the following statement in the post’s Front Matter YAML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mathjax: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Here are some examples collected from the MathJax page: 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lorenz Equations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{aligned}
\dot{x} &amp; = \sigma(y-x) \\
\dot{y} &amp; = \rho x - y - xz \\
\dot{z} &amp; = -\beta z + xy
\end{aligned} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^{\!\!2} \leq
 \left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k^2 \right) \left( \sum_{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right)&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Cross Product Formula&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\mathbf{V}_1 \times \mathbf{V}_2 =
   \begin{vmatrix}
    \mathbf{i} &amp; \mathbf{j} &amp; \mathbf{k} \\
    \frac{\partial X}{\partial u} &amp; \frac{\partial Y}{\partial u} &amp; 0 \\
    \frac{\partial X}{\partial v} &amp; \frac{\partial Y}{\partial v} &amp; 0 \\
   \end{vmatrix} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The probability of getting (k) heads when flipping (n) coins is:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;P(E) = {n \choose k} p^k (1-p)^{ n-k}&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An Identity of Ramanujan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\frac{1}{(\sqrt{\phi \sqrt{5}}-\phi) e^{\frac25 \pi}} =
     1+\frac{e^{-2\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-4\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-6\pi}}
      {1+\frac{e^{-8\pi}} {1+\ldots} } } }&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Rogers-Ramanujan Identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
1 +  \frac{q^2}{(1-q)}+\frac{q^6}{(1-q)(1-q^2)}+\cdots =
    \prod_{j=0}^{\infty}\frac{1}{(1-q^{5j+2})(1-q^{5j+3})},
     \quad\quad \text{for $|q|&lt;1$}. %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maxwell’s Equations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align}
  \nabla \times \vec{\mathbf{B}} -\, \frac1c\, \frac{\partial\vec{\mathbf{E}}}{\partial t} &amp; = \frac{4\pi}{c}\vec{\mathbf{j}} \\
  \nabla \cdot \vec{\mathbf{E}} &amp; = 4 \pi \rho \\
  \nabla \times \vec{\mathbf{E}}\, +\, \frac1c\, \frac{\partial\vec{\mathbf{B}}}{\partial t} &amp; = \vec{\mathbf{0}} \\
  \nabla \cdot \vec{\mathbf{B}} &amp; = 0
\end{align} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, while display equations look good for a page of samples, the
ability to mix math and text in a paragraph is also important.  This
expression $(\sqrt{3x-1}+(1+x)^2)$ is an example of an inline equation.  As
you see, MathJax equations can be used this way as well, without unduly
disturbing the spacing between lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In MathJax I use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$...$$&lt;/code&gt; or (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\begin{equation(*)}...\end{equation(*)}&lt;/code&gt; also works) for displayed equations and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$....$&lt;/code&gt; for inline equations. Take care of &amp;gt;,&amp;lt; and &amp;amp;, because they have special meanings in .html files. If your post/page is not displaying the equations properly, try to wrap the equations between &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;raw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;endraw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/06/sample-mathjax-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ianrahman.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/sample-posts/2014/01/06/sample-mathjax-post.html</guid>
        
        <category>sample post</category>
        
        <category>mathjax</category>
        
        
        <category>hmfaysal-omega-theme</category>
        
        <category>Sample-Posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
